James Hernandez

IT Support Specialist

Springfield, MA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/James-Hernandez/5dd5926a40b265e3

Certified Computer Network Management School graduate with proficiency in Tier One technical support, break-fix and help desk. Skilled in installing, configuring, troubleshooting, and maintenance of laptops and desktops. Experienced with virtual machines using Hyper-V and troubleshooting networks.

TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Support Specialist

IT Pathways - Springfield, MA - April 2017 to Present

IT Support Specialist for the Springfield and Worcester MA offices for the Pathways by Molina health organization.

IRT Technician

Konica Minolta USA - Windsor, CT - August 2016 to November 2016

Responsibilities

Assisted copier technicians with submitting incident requests and transferring them to the proper department for assistance.

IT Support Specialist

St. Francis Hospital - Hartford, CT - February 2016 to June 2016

Level 1 Helpdesk support

Call center troubleshooting customer assistance at St. Francis Hospital in Hartford CT

Responsibilities

Assisted clients with software and hardware issues which also required occasional remote assistance and determining the proper escalation of tickets.

Skills Used

Great listening and verbal skills to help clients with common computer issues and quick resolve of those issues either through verbal assistance through phone or remote assistance.

Digital Solutions Associate

Konica Minolta USA - Windsor, CT - November 2014 to February 2016

1

Call center troubleshooting/customer assistance

Responsibilities

Help customers over the phone with questions they may have with the copiers, accounts, etc. Help troubleshoot any issues they may have with the copiers, or connect them to the right department for service or questions. Accomplishments

Earned numerous certificates related to copier support such as: Field Resource Engineer and other similar in house prerequisite courses for the FRE certificate and continually building a knowledge base of the equipment that we help troubleshoot for our clients.

Skills Used

Great phone and verbal skills are a must when interacting with clients. Quick thinking and the ability to work through difficult calls to help customers. Use of the knowledge I gain from learning the numerous machines that are offered by Konica Minolta. Knowledge and use of SAP ticket system.

IT Support

Fit Solutions LLC - Enfield, CT - October 2014 to October 2014

to October 2014

Contractual work for the Massachusetts Dept. of Health deploying new PC terminals.

IT / Help Desk support. (Internship)

Peter Pan Bus Lines Inc - Springfield, MA - May 2014 to June 2014

Updating fleet firmware for MDVR (Mobile Digital Video Recording) system remotely. Joining employees to the company domain and installing required software to their laptops, and setting up printers for deployment to various bus depots.

IT Support

Peak Systems Inc - Hartford, CT - April 2014 to April 2014

to April 2014

Contractual work for UBS Bank. Migration of OS systems and software from Windows XP to Windows 7.

Prior work history available upon request.

EDUCATION

Certification in Successfully

Branford Hall Career Institute - Springfield, MA 2013 to 2014

Associates in Applied Science in Design Drafting

Queensborough Community College - Bayside, NY 1989 to 1991

SKILLS

SAP (1 year), ACCESS (Less than 1 year), AUTOCAD (Less than 1 year), CITRIX (Less than 1 year), DHCP (Less than 1 year), DNS (Less than 1 year), ELECTRONIC HEALTH RECORDS (Less than 1 year)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Operating Systems: Deploying, installing, configuring, troubleshooting and securing Windows XP, 7, 8 and 10.Windows server 2008r2 & 2012r2. Repair and installation of desktop/laptop parts and accessories. Windows OS migrations and upgrades. Remote set up, IP addressing, DNS, DHCP, network infrastructure, diagnostics, wired and wireless. Basic knowledge of Linux Operating systems (Ubuntu, Mint, FreeNAS, PFSense). Software: MS Office 2007, 2010, and 2013(Outlook, Excel, Access, Word). Basic knowledge, and understanding of AutoCAD systems, Hyper-V, VMware virtual software and use of Service Now, Remedy and SAP ticketing systems. Knowledge of SCCM and VNC remote software tools as well as Citrix based software tools. Familiar with EPIC (Electronic Health Records Software).